<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-14T14:44:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Building Ana’s Website, Pt 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Ana's Website, Pt 3" /><published>2019-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-3">&lt;p&gt;Hey there, welcome to the 3rd part of this series that I’ve been writing, about building my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@anarlguerra&quot;&gt;Ana Guerra&lt;/a&gt; a personal website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.byvasco.com/articles/building-anas-website-pt-2&quot;&gt;On part 2&lt;/a&gt; we drafted all the required pages for the website: the About Me page, which works like a home page, the Podcast page, Blog, Newsletter and Contacts page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a good starting point. I’ve created a rough layout of how this might all look without using any images and colors, but I already used the two chosen typefaces (Raleway and InterUI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, me and Ana were pretty happy with what came out. So the next step is to give these grayscale compositions a bit of life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;abouthome-page&quot;&gt;About/Home page&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from the beginning, this is how the About/Home page looks after going through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2019-03-07-building-anas-website-pt-3/home-top.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ana's Website - Home page, top part.&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we have the Hero, with an introduction to who Ana is and a big “Let’s Talk” call to action, that takes us to the Contact page once clicked. We also decided to add this confetti looking thing on the background with the emojis, to give this top section some color. The emojis are a TV, some headphones and an open book: the same emojis Ana uses on her newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above that, there’s the first content section: the Podcast, with the last 4 episodes and a link to the Podcast page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each other section (Blog and Newsletter) will have these big repeated titles, with a text label in-between, indicating the sharing frequency. So for example, because Ana shares a new podcast episode around once per week, we wrote “An Episode a Week or So” in that label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another detail is that the titles should be constantly moving, sliding from right to left, overflowing the page. I think this will make things look a bit more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because these sections are visually similar, I wanted to find a way to clearly divide them. I ended up with these big fat titles that work really well, creating a lot of contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2019-03-07-building-anas-website-pt-3/home-bottom.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ana's Website - Home page, bottom part.&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Newsletter section works as an introduction and clicking on the “Find Out More” button, we’ll be taken to the Newsletter page, with a bit more information. There’s also a small excerpt of a real Newsletter Ana shared on the right side, as you can see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The footer remained as it was before, with icons/links to all social media channels that Ana is at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;podcast-and-blog-pages&quot;&gt;Podcast and Blog pages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two pages basically follow the exact same layout, excluding the fact that the podcasts are in a 4 column grid, and the blog posts in a 3 column one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2019-03-07-building-anas-website-pt-3/podcast-blog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ana's Website - Podcast and Blog pages.&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works perfectly for the purpose it has, and it fits the overall visual style for the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and in these “interior” pages the titles are static&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;newsletter-page&quot;&gt;Newsletter page&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It follows the same 2 column layout from the Home page, but this time there’s a bit more information. The call-to-action remains the same, which takes us to the Whatsapp page to join it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above that, we have a couple of bullet points giving some more details about the newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2019-03-07-building-anas-website-pt-3/newsletter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ana's Website - Newsletter page.&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here, the “demo” on the right side is actually scrollable, so instead of just a small excerpt, we have a full-size newsletter message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact-page&quot;&gt;Contact page&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s the Contact page, with a link to send Ana an email or to open her Twitter profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2019-03-07-building-anas-website-pt-3/contact.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ana's Website - Contact page.&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on the bottom, her last 10 Instagram pictures or videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re really liking how this came up. It’s simple, and not too much information so it’s straight to the point: Ana’s content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;next-step-lets-code&quot;&gt;Next step: let’s code&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as you can imagine, the next step is to make this baby get out of Sketch and give it the life it deserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of all this is to make Ana’s content to be the main focus. And that content needs to be managed by its maker! So, for that reason, this is going to be transformed into a custom Wordpress theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest: I’m not experienced in working with Wordpress development. I have no knowledge of what the best workflow is, or the best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment I’m writing this (March 6), the front-end code is already created and I’m learning Wordpress development on the fly, but I’m confident I’ll be able to pull this off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon! 👋🏼&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.byvasco.com/articles/building-anas-website-pt-2&quot;&gt;← Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey there, welcome to the 3rd part of this series that I’ve been writing, about building my friend Ana Guerra a personal website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building Ana’s Website, Pt 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Ana's Website, Pt 2" /><published>2018-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-2/">&lt;p&gt;Onto the second part of this series where I’m creating a website for my friend Ana Guerra and documenting the process of doing so! To get some context of what’s going on, here’s the 1st part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is also doing it on her podcast, here’s the first episode, the second one is coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-quick-recap-from-the-last-article&quot;&gt;A quick recap from the last article:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We know what kind of website this is and what the goal is — to serve as a digital home for all the content and projects Ana has.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we also know all the pages needed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Decided on what direction to follow regarding look and feel for this.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Got the color palette and the main typeface.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And finally, I created the folder structure on my computer for this project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, I have kind of a clear idea of how the final product could look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;starting-out&quot;&gt;Starting out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a confession of a bad habit I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, in the starting phase of a project, I go straight to Google or Dribbble to grab some inspiration. I think this is a bad habit because I’m not exercising my mind to come up with an original solution for the given problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s also another side of the coin. I don’t believe in pure, 100% originality. Because I need some kind of influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do believe is that I’m in a constant “sponge mode”. Constantly observing the world around me, the products and interfaces I interact with, the movies I watch and the books that I read. As a result, I’m building like a mental library of ideas that I can use in my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nJPERZDfyWc&quot;&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/a&gt; by Kirby Ferguson is a great video that relates to this line of thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this time, I grabbed a pen and just sketched the ideas that were floating around in my head. Nothing fancy or stunning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-the-screen&quot;&gt;To the screen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I feel that I dumped all my ideas onto paper, I move to the computer, where I start to play around with typography and colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-12-23-building-anas-website-pt-2/image-1.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my process is kind of organic. What I mean by this, is that I don’t follow a strict path or series of steps. I like to go back and forth between my notepad and my computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at this time that I realized we should find a typeface for body copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://rsms.me/inter/&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-12-23-building-anas-website-pt-2/image-2.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ana has been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Raleway&quot;&gt;Raleway&lt;/a&gt; across all her assets, and I ended up finding &lt;a href=&quot;https://rsms.me/inter/&quot;&gt;Inter UI&lt;/a&gt;, a somewhat neutral looking typeface that was designed to be easily legible on computer screens. I love how they look when combined!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-the-first-home-concept&quot;&gt;Creating the first Home concept&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After exploring a bit, I started to make a basic mockup for the Home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that went through my mind was that, besides the blog posts, there’s not much text to put on the website. And I wanted to find a way to somehow use typography to keep things interesting but at the same time maintaining the clean and simple vibe to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I played around a bit and ended up creating this concept for the Home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-12-23-building-anas-website-pt-2/image-3.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no pictures or colors, I just wanted to figure out how I could layout the different sections to use the content we have using the chosen typefaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick overview of its different parts, starting with the top section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-12-23-building-anas-website-pt-2/image-4.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;text-smaller caption&quot;&gt;The top section is as simple as it gets&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The header will have the same picture of Ana uses on all social media channels on the left, and a basic navigation menu on the right, with links to the other pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the “Hello you” and the “This is Ana Guerra” blocks help to create some movement, instead of just having a straight, centered column of text. And it’s also the same way she introduces herself on the podcast, so we can keep that consistent here on the website!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-12-23-building-anas-website-pt-2/image-5.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on those 3 sections (Podcast, Blog and Newsletter), the idea is that each title works as a divider between them, and while we’re scrolling through the page it slowly slides to the left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think &lt;a href=&quot;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Raleway&quot;&gt;Raleway&lt;/a&gt; looks great on larger sizes, especially on heavier weights, and it works wonders for this concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This title part actually started with a dash in between the words. But then I had the idea of replacing that for a piece of text that communicates the posting frequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-12-23-building-anas-website-pt-2/image-6.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;text-smaller caption&quot;&gt;The initial idea and a small change afterward&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Newsletter section is a bit different than the other two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-12-23-building-anas-website-pt-2/image-7.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.whatsapp.com/invite/H7NiyFlukld7scG6OuDnPp&quot;&gt;The newsletter&lt;/a&gt; is delivered through Whatsapp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the idea here is to have like a mobile device on the right side, displaying the Whatsapp’s chat UI, on the left a button to join and another to the dedicated Newsletter page (which will also serve as a landing page) in order to get more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To finish things up, there’s the footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-12-23-building-anas-website-pt-2/image-8.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It basically consists of a series of icons that link to all the different platforms where Ana is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in this particular case I almost did no research to check out what’s currently out there, mainly because I got to that concept I showed you above pretty quickly after exploring for a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already had a list of 4 or 5 websites that served as a reference, that we collected on the first meeting we had. Other than that I only navigated a bit through my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.pt/vascogmm/typography/&quot;&gt;Typography Board on Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://typeonly.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Typeonly&lt;/a&gt; to get the creative juices flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;communication-and-getting-feedback&quot;&gt;Communication and getting feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and Ana have been using Whatsapp to talk and to get her opinions and feedback regarding the work, I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://marvelapp.com/&quot;&gt;Marvel&lt;/a&gt; to do that job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-things-to-do&quot;&gt;Next things to do&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to create the mockups for all the remaining pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I get all done, I’ll bring some colors in and take care of things in a more detailed level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon in part 3! 👋🏼&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Onto the second part of this series where I’m creating a website for my friend Ana Guerra and documenting the process of doing so! To get some context of what’s going on, here’s the 1st part.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building Ana’s Website, Pt 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Ana's Website, Pt 1" /><published>2018-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/building-anas-website-pt-1">&lt;p&gt;Starting from the beginning. My friend Ana Guerra started thinking about creating a newsletter and we talked about creating some kind of landing page for that. However, there are a few more things she’s into — she also writes and has a podcast. So we thought we should take it a step further and just create a full website to serve as her personal home on the internet to house every project she has going on, and for future stuff as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the beginning of a series where me and Ana will document the full process of building her website. I’ll write here on Medium and on my website, and she’s doing it on her podcast. &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/anarlguerra/episodes/Vasco-is-building-my-website-EP-1-e2hfas/a-a698fv&quot;&gt;Here’s the first episode&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we landed on this conclusion, we met for a coffee after work to chat a bit about what this website should and shouldn’t do, and what content should be in there. Basically, we defined the general concept/idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-kind-of-website-will-this-be&quot;&gt;What kind of website will this be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would call this a personal website. On the home page there’s gonna be a short introduction of who Ana is and what she does, and then &lt;strong&gt;3 different sections&lt;/strong&gt; to showcase the different types of content she creates (podcast, the blog, and the newsletter), where the podcast and the blog sections will have the most recent episodes/posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the home page, there will be a few other pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a page specifically for the podcast with all the episodes
the blog, with all the blog posts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a page for the newsletter&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;a contact page&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;and in the future we might build a gear page, to showcase all the different equipment she uses on a daily basis&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;colors-typography-and-overall-feel&quot;&gt;Colors, typography, and overall feel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ana has already defined the color palette for her brand, and she’s also been using Raleway as the main typeface, so that’s awesome. I might introduce another one a bit more neutral for body copy, but I still need to explore a bit on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-11-17-building-anas-website-pt-1/image-1.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy that the colors are pretty bright and vivid, because that reenforces who she is: a person full of energy and with lots of will to do stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the goal is to make this look simple, modern, young and to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-steps&quot;&gt;First steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was to create the folder structure on my computer. I have 4 different folders here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docs&lt;/strong&gt;: where I’ll save all kinds of documents Ana sends me&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assets&lt;/strong&gt;: for images, icons, etc&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;: this will be where all the Sketch files will live&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shared&lt;/strong&gt;: the folder where I’ll put everything I want to share with Ana, like final designs, assets for her to use, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was highly inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TU_O9BOWyVE&amp;amp;ab_channel=JesseShowalter&quot;&gt;Jesse Showalter’s method&lt;/a&gt;. I recommend you to check out his channel for awesome design related content!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I also like to do is to create a couple of artboards in Sketch to build the color palette and even though in this case it’s nothing complex, I also like to create the sitemap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I make sure I get all the written content that should be displayed on the website so that I can &lt;strong&gt;design around the content and not the other way around&lt;/strong&gt; — after all, the content is the most important thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok so next I’ll be exploring a bit on pen and paper just to get my ideas going on how the layout could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing is to look for other people’s personal websites just to get a sense of what’s out there, and after that, it’s time to start designing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave this for the next post, which shouldn’t take too long to come out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you in part 2! 👋🏼&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Starting from the beginning. My friend Ana Guerra started thinking about creating a newsletter and we talked about creating some kind of landing page for that. However, there are a few more things she’s into — she also writes and has a podcast. So we thought we should take it a step further and just create a full website to serve as her personal home on the internet to house every project she has going on, and for future stuff as well!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Design and Fixing Old Cars</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/on-design-and-fixing-old-cars" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Design and Fixing Old Cars" /><published>2018-10-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/on-design-and-fixing-old-cars</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/on-design-and-fixing-old-cars">&lt;!--
  Creates the image path.
  If there's no &quot;image-path&quot; parameter, use the post title instead.
  Image comes from &quot;assets/posts/&lt;date-title&gt;&quot;
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- This is just a regular image, coming from &quot;assets/images&quot; --&gt;
  &amp;lt;img
    src=”/assets/images/image-cover.png”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my car just broke something while I was driving — I’m literally writing this while on the side of a highway waiting for the tow truck to arrive, and I thought it would be a perfect time to write this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My professional life is dedicated to creating and designing things, but like a lot of people, I have some hobbies as well. In my case, one of them happens to be messing around and fixing my own (old) cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like old cars because almost everything is made of mechanical parts and systems. I’m the owner of a 1990 Mk2 Golf that is currently being restored, and my daily car, a 1993 Honda Civic that went through a small restoration a few months ago as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting part is that, with time, I’ve realized that there are a few concepts that are present and apply to both my work and this hobby of mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;be-patient&quot;&gt;Be patient&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose this one to be the first on the list because I struggle a bit with it. Patience, in my opinion, is something that is kind of difficult to have (at least for me), but the return of actually having it is pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I rush things I will probably end up with poor design work or something in my car that won’t work properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if I have the patience, and if I take the time to at least try to do things right, I’ll probably end up with better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;stay-positive&quot;&gt;Stay positive&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, it’s not a great feeling to be on the side of a highway with a broken car, not knowing what the problem is, and not knowing how much money it will cost to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I only have a couple of mindsets I can have here: a negative, and a positive one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negative thinking would lead me to complain about how crap this car is (and it’s not, actually), or about the fact that I hadn’t had a meal in 5 hours and I’m slowly starving waiting for the tow truck to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is: I have no control over this situation, and if there’s anything I can do about it, I’m sure complaining is not one of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have one option, though: I can filter something positive out of this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ok, it sucks to be here. But at least I have my laptop here with me and I can start to write this article!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my design work I also try to keep a positive mindset. Because I’m aware that positivity attracts positivity. That way, I feel more creative, happier and more optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;use-mistakes-as-a-learning-experiences&quot;&gt;Use mistakes as a learning experiences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night, I was trying to change the starter engine of my Golf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first time doing it and I ended up fucking things up — due to the way the starter engine is mounted, it was helping the car’s engine to stay in its place. So, as I removed the last bolt, the engine literally fell down a few centimeters, and as it did that, an electrical plug disconnected (and I haven’t realized that). I was able to install a new starter, but when I gave ignition, the car didn’t start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened at around 3 AM. I was working on the road, I was tired and frustrated, so I ended up “giving up” that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, a friend of mine went with me to try and see what the problem was. Well, in just 5 minutes of looking at the engine bay, he quickly found that electrical plug that had disconnected, which was preventing the car from starting. The plug was connected, and the car immediately started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was clearly clueless about this, mainly because it was the first time I was changing a starter. My mistake was basic: I didn’t support the car’s engine before doing anything else. But now I learned, and I can certainly assure that this won’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all make mistakes, and as a young designer, I’m obviously making a lot. But the key is to take responsibility, take a step back, see what went wrong, and learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dont-force-it&quot;&gt;Don’t force it&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one will be short: rule of thumb, if a bolt, for example, needs to be forced to be installed, I’m probably doing something wrong and I might end up breaking or damaging something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, I can apply this when talking about inspiration. If I’m not feeling inspired, I think there’s no way of forcing good work to come out. Might as well take a break, go read a book, watch a video or even get out of the house for some fresh air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;everythings-better-in-my-head&quot;&gt;Everything’s better in my head&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my Civic (my daily car) went for a paint job, I was already imagining it with its new color, with a perfect coat of fresh and shiny paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was perfect in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for the price I paid, it wasn’t even a realistic thought. When the car came from the paint job I quickly spotted some details that were not as I wanted, and that was bugging me a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is: generally speaking, it was actually pretty good! But in my head, I could only think about those details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve created unrealistic expectations&lt;/strong&gt;, and the final result was not matching them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I think of an idea for a website, an app, or something else, it always seems better in my head then what will look like after the design is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, it comes down to accepting it and not creating those huge expectations that lead to disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">&amp;lt;img src=”/assets/images/image-cover.png” /&amp;gt;</summary></entry></feed>