<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-16T01:37:08+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How I organize Sass projects</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/organizing-sass-projects" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I organize Sass projects" /><published>2019-09-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/organizing-sass-projects-</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/organizing-sass-projects">&lt;p&gt;These last few days I’ve been busy working on cleaning all the stylesheets from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hole19golf.com&quot;&gt;H19&lt;/a&gt; website. It may seem tedious and boring but I’m actually enjoying it, I like the idea of transforming chaos into order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I work with Sass, I wanted to get a stable workflow and a way of organizing my files in a specific order. I have also recently started to learn and work with React, which uses components to structure everything, and that inspired me to organize the Sass files in this way, at least for larger projects. So let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea is to separate things into 3 parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Base&lt;/strong&gt;: things like base styles, resets, typography, variables, mixins, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: the different pieces of the website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout&lt;/strong&gt;: how the components relate to each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think like this: a component works with padding, a layout works with margins. But let’s see how this might work in a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I do whenever I start a new project is to first create the folders where the code will live, then the “index” partial for each of them, and lastly the main file where those 3 partials will be imported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/articles/organizing-sass-projects/getting-started.jpg&quot; /&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfect. So now we don’t mess around with that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;main.scss&lt;/code&gt; because its main job is to import those 3 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;base&quot;&gt;Base&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that created, we can start to create the base styles. I usually have a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_base.scss&lt;/code&gt;, a&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_typography.scss&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_variables.scss&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_helpers.scss&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_reset.scss&lt;/code&gt; and that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; before the name of the file so that Sass knows that it’s a partial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/articles/organizing-sass-projects/base.jpg&quot; /&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we just need to import each of these in our &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_base-index.scss&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;components&quot;&gt;Components&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to take care of the components. Let’s take a look at this example right here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/articles/organizing-sass-projects/website-example.jpg&quot; /&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, this fictional web page has these 3 components: header, content and the footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I do this is basically by creating a partial for each of those components. So we would have &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_header.scss&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_content.scss&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_footer.scss&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then all those partials are imported on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_components-index.scss&lt;/code&gt; file and that’s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we could go in even more detail and assume that the header would have a logo component and a menu component for example. So I would create a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;header&lt;/code&gt; folder, and inside that, I’d place the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_header.scss&lt;/code&gt; but also a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_logo.scss&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_menu.scss&lt;/code&gt;. And not to forget a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_header-index.scss&lt;/code&gt; to import all those, which is then imported on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_components-index.scss&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/articles/organizing-sass-projects/components.jpg&quot; /&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;layout&quot;&gt;Layout&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we have the layouts. In here I like to at least have a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_structure.scss&lt;/code&gt; file where I define my containers and all that, and this is also the place where I create a file to control the layout for each page of the website I’m creating. So if I’m working with a website that has a Home and an About page, I’d have a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_page-home.scss&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_page-about.scss&lt;/code&gt; file. Nothing too complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what are we doing in these layouts? Let’s take a look at our website again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Img&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re controlling the margins between each component of the page. In this case, for example, we would do something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/articles/organizing-sass-projects/layout.jpg&quot; /&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;real-example&quot;&gt;Real example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an oversimplified example, so let’s take a look at how I’m structuring the Sass on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hole19golf.com&quot;&gt;H19&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the base folder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the layouts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see this has a bit more stuff to work with. A useful tip is to separate everything into folders as it helps to keep everything organized, and it’s much easier to find the code you’re looking for. And I find it to be pretty easy to scale as the project grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how I’m currently working but I’m always looking to improve my process so this is a constant work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you find this useful and that it helps with your future projects. See you next time, and happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">These last few days I’ve been busy working on cleaning all the stylesheets from the H19 website. It may seem tedious and boring but I’m actually enjoying it, I like the idea of transforming chaos into order.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating content, documenting and giving value</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/content-documenting-value" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating content, documenting and giving value" /><published>2019-09-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/content-documenting-value</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/content-documenting-value">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been somewhat thoughtful and slightly overthinking the topic of creating content, and building a personal brand for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, why even bother creating a personal brand? In my opinion is one of the greatest assets we can have, specially for the work side of our lives. My motivation is to be able to connect with people from all over the world, to create future opportunities, and to do something that is actually valuable or help someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this last part – giving value – is what have been bothering me for quite some time. Because what do I know, right? I’m currently 22, and even though I’ve been working as a designer and a developer since I was 17, I really don’t think I have something special, or some special knowledge to give to people. So ok, I can’t go through that route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s this &lt;strong&gt;document, don’t create&lt;/strong&gt; concept GaryVee came up with, and if you follow his work like me, you’re most likely aware of what I’m talking about. If you don’t it’s basically this: we should document what we’re doing, and position ourselves not like an expert on something (if we’re not), but rather as someone who is trying to become something. So we should document our process on becoming a web designer, on becoming a developer, or a writer, or a racing driver, or whatever we want to become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I love that, because it alleviates me from not feeling accredited to give advice, I can just document what I’m doing and just give my opinions. However, I still couldn’t understand how that could possibly bring value to somebody, because at the end of the day I’d be just constantly talking about myself… Until about 10 minutes ago!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RVKofRN1dyI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on my lunch break, listening to Gary’s video “Document, Don’t Create” for the 1000th time (👆🏼 this one right here) and there’s a clip of him talking where he says this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If I actually, from where I started, go on to buy a 4B$ sports organization and I documented the entire journey… My words are motivating and I’m good at that. But, the reason I do DailyVee and the reason I’m documenting so much is: if I can put out a body of work 40 years from now that showed the process of a young man that put in the work, had the vision, did it the right way, tried to help people along the way and then I actually accomplish it, well that becomes a real great American Dream story”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that got me thinking, because that’s the value I’m adding. Me and everyone else that’s documenting their journeys. We can be an inspiration for the future people that come after us. And  that can be in 40 years, on in 40 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thepatwalls&quot;&gt;@thepatwalls&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/levelsio&quot;&gt;@levelsio&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ajlkn&quot;&gt;@ajlkn&lt;/a&gt; : they’re doing their own stuff, documenting the process while doing it, and sharing with the world, which is quite inspiring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, just a quick thought I wanted to put into words because I want to do this. I want to record the process of me trying to go where I want to go, and the things that I learn along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been somewhat thoughtful and slightly overthinking the topic of creating content, and building a personal brand for myself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Design and Fixing Old Cars</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/on-design-and-fixing-old-cars" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Design and Fixing Old Cars" /><published>2018-10-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/on-design-and-fixing-old-cars</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/on-design-and-fixing-old-cars">&lt;p&gt;So my car just broke something while I was driving — I’m literally writing this while on the side of a highway waiting for the tow truck to arrive, and I thought it would be a perfect time to write this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My professional life is dedicated to creating and designing things, but like a lot of people, I have some hobbies as well. In my case, one of them happens to be messing around and fixing my own (old) cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like old cars because almost everything is made of mechanical parts and systems. I’m the owner of a 1990 Mk2 Golf that is currently being restored, and my daily car, a 1993 Honda Civic that went through a small restoration a few months ago as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting part is that, with time, I’ve realized that there are a few concepts that are present and apply to both my work and this hobby of mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;be-patient&quot;&gt;Be patient&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose this one to be the first on the list because I struggle a bit with it. Patience, in my opinion, is something that is kind of difficult to have (at least for me), but the return of actually having it is pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I rush things I will probably end up with poor design work or something in my car that won’t work properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if I have the patience, and if I take the time to at least try to do things right, I’ll probably end up with better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;stay-positive&quot;&gt;Stay positive&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, it’s not a great feeling to be on the side of a highway with a broken car, not knowing what the problem is, and not knowing how much money it will cost to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I only have a couple of mindsets I can have here: a negative, and a positive one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negative thinking would lead me to complain about how crap this car is (and it’s not, actually), or about the fact that I hadn’t had a meal in 5 hours and I’m slowly starving waiting for the tow truck to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is: I have no control over this situation, and if there’s anything I can do about it, I’m sure complaining is not one of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have one option, though: I can filter something positive out of this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ok, it sucks to be here. But at least I have my laptop here with me and I can start to write this article!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my design work I also try to keep a positive mindset. Because I’m aware that positivity attracts positivity. That way, I feel more creative, happier and more optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;use-mistakes-as-a-learning-experiences&quot;&gt;Use mistakes as a learning experiences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night, I was trying to change the starter engine of my Golf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first time doing it and I ended up fucking things up — due to the way the starter engine is mounted, it was helping the car’s engine to stay in its place. So, as I removed the last bolt, the engine literally fell down a few centimeters, and as it did that, an electrical plug disconnected (and I haven’t realized that). I was able to install a new starter, but when I gave ignition, the car didn’t start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened at around 3 AM. I was working on the road, I was tired and frustrated, so I ended up “giving up” that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, a friend of mine went with me to try and see what the problem was. Well, in just 5 minutes of looking at the engine bay, he quickly found that electrical plug that had disconnected, which was preventing the car from starting. The plug was connected, and the car immediately started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was clearly clueless about this, mainly because it was the first time I was changing a starter. My mistake was basic: I didn’t support the car’s engine before doing anything else. But now I learned, and I can certainly assure that this won’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all make mistakes, and as a young designer, I’m obviously making a lot. But the key is to take responsibility, take a step back, see what went wrong, and learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dont-force-it&quot;&gt;Don’t force it&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one will be short: rule of thumb, if a bolt, for example, needs to be forced to be installed, I’m probably doing something wrong and I might end up breaking or damaging something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, I can apply this when talking about inspiration. If I’m not feeling inspired, I think there’s no way of forcing good work to come out. Might as well take a break, go read a book, watch a video or even get out of the house for some fresh air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;everythings-better-in-my-head&quot;&gt;Everything’s better in my head&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my Civic (my daily car) went for a paint job, I was already imagining it with its new color, with a perfect coat of fresh and shiny paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was perfect in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for the price I paid, it wasn’t even a realistic thought. When the car came from the paint job I quickly spotted some details that were not as I wanted, and that was bugging me a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is: generally speaking, it was actually pretty good! But in my head, I could only think about those details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve created unrealistic expectations&lt;/strong&gt;, and the final result was not matching them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I think of an idea for a website, an app, or something else, it always seems better in my head then what will look like after the design is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, it comes down to accepting it and not creating those huge expectations that lead to disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So my car just broke something while I was driving — I’m literally writing this while on the side of a highway waiting for the tow truck to arrive, and I thought it would be a perfect time to write this article.</summary></entry></feed>